<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cody Markelz</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Cody Markelz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Cody Markelz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biodiversity and Fire</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/biodiversity-fire/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/biodiversity-fire/</guid><description>About project A new project that combines data science, modeling, biodiversity, invasive species and fire to answer questions across Californian ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/postdoc_projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/postdoc_projects/</guid><description>Physiological Systems Biology of Competition in Brassica rapa Plants growing in dense stands compete with one another for light resources at the top of the canopy. When plants sense neighbors through the phytochrome photoreceptor system they become apical dominant and grow upwards to maximize light capture. This response is termed shade avoidance and has very important ecological and agronomic consequences if plant resources are used for competitive growth instead of reproductive output.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/about/</guid><description>I am generally interested in the complexities of nature and choose problems that require at least a paper and pencil to work out. I use data, mathematical models, and illustrations as tools to understand the beauty and complexity of nature.
Currently, I am an Accenture Global Environmental Change Fellow at Berkeley Institute for Data Science (BIDS) working at the intersection between invasive species, climate change and wildfire in Californian ecosystems. My project involves developing probabilistic models that work with newly collated datasets and meta-data to work across environmental scales to understand wildfire spread and impact.</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/cv/</guid><description>Current Affiliation Accenture Global Environmental Change Fellow- Berkeley Institute for Data Science (BIDS) 2021-present Previous Affiliations Co-Founder and VP of Genomics - Rev Genomics 2016-20 NSF Postdoctoral Fellow - UC Davis Department of Plant Biology 2014-17 UC Davis Data Science Initiative 2016-17 Education Ph.D. Plant Biology, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign - 2012 Advisor: Dr. Andrew Leakey B.S. Integrative Biology, Minor: Chemistry, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign - 2007 Grants and Awards PI: NSF- Postdoctoral Fellowships in Biology- Develop a systems level model of resource allocation and partitioning in Brassica rapa to predict growth across multiple genotypes and environments.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/publications/</guid><description>Google Scholar Profile
Publications Baker RL, Leong W, Brock MT, Rubin MJ, Markelz RJC, Welch S, Maloof JN, Weinig C (2019) Integrating transcriptomic network reconstruction and QTL analyses reveals mechanistic connections between genomic architecture and Brassica rapa development. PLoS Genetics 15 (9), e1008367. paper
Markelz RJC 1,Covington MF 1, Devisetty UK, Brock M, Weinig C, Maloof JN (2017) Using RNA-Seq for genomic scaffold placement, correcting assemblies, and genetic map creation in a common Brassica rapa mapping population.</description></item><item><title>Introduction data post with cycling data</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2021/03/15/2021-03-15-tidy-data-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:07:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2021/03/15/2021-03-15-tidy-data-intro/</guid><description>Cycle Commuting Data For the last few years I commuted to work most days by bicycle along the Martin Luther King Jr. Regional Shoreline Park park in Oakland, CA. This will be a series of data science posts exploring personal data collected by my smart watch and publicly available weather, nature and biodiversity data. It is my hope that this will show into the brain of how a data scientist thinks, learns, asks questions, creates models, and visualizes data from right in their back yard.</description></item><item><title>PhD</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/phd_projects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/phd_projects/</guid><description>PhD Dissertation Projects During graduate school I was interested in doing a mixture of field, molecular, computational, and engineering projects. Thanks in part to the freedom afforded by a NSF Graduate Research Fellowship, I designed research projects to answer open questions in the climate change literature that incorporated these four components. Here is a copy of my dissertation.
Abstract The balance between photosynthetic carbon dioxide (CO2) assimilation and respiratory CO2release influence plant growth, crop yields, and the ability of terrestrial ecosystems to offset ~2-3 Gt CO2yr -1 of anthropogenic emissions.</description></item><item><title>Outreach</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/science_outreach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/science_outreach/</guid><description>Dr. Sharon B. Gray Memorial Foundation &amp;ldquo;I feel that when the human race acquired the technology and evolved the intelligence necessary to build an industrial society, it also acquired the moral obligation to understand and monitor its impact on the rest of the world.&amp;rdquo; -Dr. Sharon B. Gray
Dr. Sharon Gray was a bright human being with a passion for science and mentoring women. This foundation has set up endowments for financially supporting women in science at UC Davis, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, American Society of Plant Biology, and the Ethiopian Agricultural Research Center (EIAR).</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/teaching/</guid><description>In an age of information abundance, the university is now a place where students come to learn active strategies for navigating this sea of information in a scientifically literate way. Through my experience I have found that one of the best ways for students to achieve this goal is to have a safe environment centered around projects where asking questions and thinking critically are encouraged. Scientific discovery is not achieved in a vacuum.</description></item><item><title>Hobbies</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/hobbies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/hobbies/</guid><description>Coming Soon!</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Trello for Project Management</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/11/18/2015-11-18-trello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 09:07:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/11/18/2015-11-18-trello/</guid><description>Motivation This quick post is an example of my scientific and collaboration work flow using the free features of Trellos. I have tried many different ways of organizing ideas and implementing GTD. Email is NOT a good way to organize projects, especially long term ones. Elaborate tag systems can help, but I found that it is more hassle than it is worth when there are other tools available. For a while I used The Secret Weapon.</description></item><item><title>Art Science Hackathon</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/01/01/2015-01-01-artsciencehack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 09:07:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/01/01/2015-01-01-artsciencehack/</guid><description>Concept I have two really good friends that are both professional designers/artists living in Chicago. Every year over the holiday break we would discuss how fun it would be to do a collaborative project, but never got around to doing one because of our busy schedules. This year we planned a few months in advance to have a hackathon style four day work session between Christmas and New Years. We wanted to move as quickly as possible and make as many ideas happen as possible in our short time frame.</description></item></channel></rss>