<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cody Markelz</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Cody Markelz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Cody Markelz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biodiversity and Fire</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/biodiversity-fire/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/biodiversity-fire/</guid><description>About project A project that combines data science, modeling, biodiversity, invasive species and fire to answer questions across Californian ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/about/</guid><description>I am generally interested in the complexities of interactions in nature and choose problems that require (at least) a paper and pencil to work out. I use data and mathematical models as tools to understand the beauty and complexity of nature. Currently, I am an Accenture Global Environmental Change Fellow at Berkeley Institute for Data Science (BIDS) working at the intersection between invasive species, climate change and wildfire in Californian ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/cv/</guid><description>Current Affiliation Accenture Global Environmental Change Fellow- Berkeley Institute for Data Science (BIDS) 2021-present Previous Affiliations Co-Founder and VP of Genomics Rev Genomics 2016-20 NSF Postdoctoral Fellow - UC Davis Department of Plant Biology 2014-17 UC Davis Data Science Initiative 2016-17 Education Ph.D. Plant Biology, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign - 2012 Advisor: Dr. Andrew Leakey B.S. Integrative Biology, Minor: Chemistry, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign - 2007 Grants and Awards PI: NSF- Postdoctoral Fellowships in Biology- Develop a systems level model of resource allocation and partitioning in Brassica rapa to predict growth across multiple genotypes and environments.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/page/publications/</guid><description>Google Scholar Profile
Peer Reviewed Publications Baker RL, Leong W, Brock MT, Rubin MJ, Markelz RJC, Welch S, Maloof JN, Weinig C (2019) Integrating transcriptomic network reconstruction and QTL analyses reveals mechanistic connections between genomic architecture and Brassica rapa development. PLoS Genetics 15 (9), e1008367. paper
Markelz RJC 1,Covington MF 1, Devisetty UK, Brock M, Weinig C, Maloof JN (2017) Using RNA-Seq for genomic scaffold placement, correcting assemblies, and genetic map creation in a common Brassica rapa mapping population.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Trello for Project Management</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/11/18/2015-11-18-trello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 09:07:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/11/18/2015-11-18-trello/</guid><description>Motivation This quick post is an example of my scientific and collaboration work flow using the free features of Trello. I have tried many different ways of organizing ideas and implementing GTD. Email is NOT a good way to organize projects, especially long term ones. Elaborate tag systems can help, but I found that it is more hassle than it is worth when there are other tools available. For a while I used The Secret Weapon.</description></item><item><title>Art Science Hackathon</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/01/01/2015-01-01-artsciencehack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 09:07:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/01/01/2015-01-01-artsciencehack/</guid><description>Title: Art + Science + Design + Rapid Idea Expression = ArtScienceHack Category: Blog Date: 2015-01-01 9:00 Modified: 2020-05-16 19:30 Author: R.J. Cody Markelz Tags: artsciencehack, outreach, design, visualization Slug: artsciencehack Summary: Summary of prototype year of #artsciencehack
Concept I have two really good friends that are both professional designers/artists living in Chicago. Every year over the holiday break we would discuss how fun it would be to do a collaborative project, but never got around to doing one because of our busy schedules.</description></item></channel></rss>