<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Cody Markelz</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Cody Markelz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Cody Markelz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:07:38 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cycling Data 1</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2021/03/15/2021-03-15-tidy-data-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:07:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2021/03/15/2021-03-15-tidy-data-intro/</guid><description>Cycle Commuting Data For the last few years I commuted to work most days by bicycle along the Martin Luther King Jr. Regional Shoreline Park park in Oakland, CA. This will be a series of data science posts exploring personal data collected by my smart watch and publicly available weather, nature and biodiversity data. It is my hope that this will show into the brain of how a data scientist thinks, learns, asks questions, creates models, and visualizes data from right in their back yard.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Trello for Project Management</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/11/18/2015-11-18-trello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 09:07:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/11/18/2015-11-18-trello/</guid><description>Motivation This quick post is an example of my scientific and collaboration work flow using the free features of Trello. I have tried many different ways of organizing ideas and implementing GTD. Email is NOT a good way to organize projects, especially long term ones. Elaborate tag systems can help, but I found that it is more hassle than it is worth when there are other tools available. For a while I used The Secret Weapon.</description></item><item><title>Art Science Hackathon</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/01/01/2015-01-01-artsciencehack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 09:07:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/2015/01/01/2015-01-01-artsciencehack/</guid><description>Concept I have two really good friends that are both professional designers/artists living in Chicago. Every year over the holiday break we would discuss how fun it would be to do a collaborative project, but never got around to doing one because of our busy schedules. This year we planned a few months in advance to have a hackathon style four day work session between Christmas and New Years. We wanted to move as quickly as possible and make as many ideas happen as possible in our short time frame.</description></item></channel></rss>