<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Cody Markelz</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Cody Markelz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Cody Markelz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Biodiversity and Fire</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/biodiversity-fire/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/biodiversity-fire/</guid><description>About project A new project that combines data science, modeling, biodiversity, invasive species and fire to answer questions across Californian ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/postdoc_projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/postdoc_projects/</guid><description>Physiological Systems Biology of Competition in Brassica rapa Plants growing in dense stands compete with one another for light resources at the top of the canopy. When plants sense neighbors through the phytochrome photoreceptor system they become apical dominant and grow upwards to maximize light capture. This response is termed shade avoidance and has very important ecological and agronomic consequences if plant resources are used for competitive growth instead of reproductive output.</description></item><item><title>PhD</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/phd_projects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/phd_projects/</guid><description>PhD Dissertation Projects During graduate school I was interested in doing a mixture of field, molecular, computational, and engineering projects. Thanks in part to the freedom afforded by a NSF Graduate Research Fellowship, I designed research projects to answer open questions in the climate change literature that incorporated these four components. Here is a copy of my dissertation.
Abstract The balance between photosynthetic carbon dioxide (CO2) assimilation and respiratory CO2release influence plant growth, crop yields, and the ability of terrestrial ecosystems to offset ~2-3 Gt CO2yr -1 of anthropogenic emissions.</description></item><item><title>Outreach</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/science_outreach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/science_outreach/</guid><description>Dr. Sharon B. Gray Memorial Foundation &amp;ldquo;I feel that when the human race acquired the technology and evolved the intelligence necessary to build an industrial society, it also acquired the moral obligation to understand and monitor its impact on the rest of the world.&amp;rdquo; -Dr. Sharon B. Gray
Dr. Sharon Gray was a bright human being with a passion for science and mentoring women. This foundation has set up endowments for financially supporting women in science at UC Davis, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, American Society of Plant Biology, and the Ethiopian Agricultural Research Center (EIAR).</description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/teaching/</guid><description>In an age of information abundance, the university is now a place where students come to learn active strategies for navigating this sea of information in a scientifically literate way. Through my experience I have found that one of the best ways for students to achieve this goal is to have a safe environment centered around projects where asking questions and thinking critically are encouraged. Scientific discovery is not achieved in a vacuum.</description></item><item><title>Hobbies</title><link>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/hobbies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rjcmarkelz.github.io/project/hobbies/</guid><description>Coming Soon!</description></item></channel></rss>